Yung-Te Chen (Peter)

Visa Status: Holding Family Reunification Visa of EU Blue Card in Berlin, Germany (I can start immediately.)

Email: peterchencc@gmail.com

Links: linkedin.com/in/peterchencc | github.com/peterchencc

Website: www.peterchen.cc

SUMMARY

6+ years of experience in software development, focusing on web platform using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, PHP. I am passionate about delivering the best user experience on product. Experienced working in startup environment and help bridge the tech feasibility and business needs.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer — Burpple

Singapore Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

- Took full ownership on web platform using Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, PostgreSQL, Redis.
- Built Burpple Beyond, a subscription-based program with Stripe payment. Maintained APIs for mobile Apps.
- Developed frontend tasks for Burpple Beyond, such as activation flow, OTP verification, referral program.
- Integrated Vue.js to built several single-page apps for cross-device features. Implemented AMP on web pages.
- Increased 30% of performance score on key pages by optimizing page loading and structure.
- Implemented CleverTap on web for marketing campaigns. Using Amplitude for product analytics data tracking.

Full Stack Web Developer — Meet.jobs

Taipei City, Taiwan Oct 2015 – Aug 2017

- As the first engineer in this startup, built job site from scratch using Ruby on Rails, MySQL, JavaScript.
- Took on product management responsibility, and accommodated revenue model evolvement.
- Set up CI/CD pipeline and agile development flow, hosted servers on Linode with Ubuntu, Nginx, Monit, Backup.
- Developed job application system includes group messages, email notification (Amazon SES), referral system.
- Built recruiting dashboard includes multi-user authorization, subscription payment with Stripe.
- Maintained admin panel includes overview of tracking data, integrated customized notification to Slack.
- Built job searching function with ElasticSearch, job crawler and CMS for blog.

Web Development Intern — Tinkerbox Studios

Singapore Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

• Part of an agile team to built a home tutor platform using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL.

Web Programmer — Appscomb.net Media, Cite Media Holding Group

Taipei City, Taiwan Sep 2012 - Jun 2014

- Top 3 for the company's performance evaluations for two seasons in a row.
- Maintained 4 websites and over 20 mobile apps API based on PHP Ctemplate framework, MySQL with FreeBSD.
- Developed push notification API and cron job that catches blogs RSS feeds and Facebook timeline data.
- Developed event ticket and promotion coupon that can be downloaded on Apple Wallet.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration, Soochow University, Taipei City, Taiwan Majored in Computer Science and Information Management Sep 2007 - Jun 2011

• Graduation final project - Worked as part of a team of 3 students to develop a simple ticket selling platform using PHP, which allowed tickets to be downloaded with a scanned encrypt QRCode.

COURSES

The Complete Junior to Senior Web Developer Roadmap (2021), Udemy

Oct 2020

• An online course to learn the technical skills for Senior Web Developers

Full-stack Advanced React & GraphQL, wesbos.com

Jun 2020

• An online course to build full stack JavaScript apps with Next.js + Apollo and GraphQL + Node.js

React For Beginners, wesbos.com

Feb 2020

• An online course to learn React.js + Firebase apps and website components

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp, Alpha Camp

Mar 2015 - May 2015

- 10 week full-time training of lectures, workshops, projects and 1:1 coding review. Built applications like forums, social networking platforms and E-commerce sites by Ruby on Rails.
- Built web platform that let users find sports coach, using Rails and MySQL with RESTful API for iOS client.

OTHERS

Side Project, TargetWatch

2020

- A web app designed for stock investors to get a snapshot of analyst ratings, price targets, and current prices on their watch lists.
- Using React + Firebase, hosted on Netlify. (https://target-watch.peterchen.cc/)

Teaching Assistant, ALPHA Camp

2017

- As a teaching assistant for full-time web development bootcamp in Singapore, held daily office hours to provide support to students' learning process.
- Reviewed curriculum and developed teaching material for online web development course.

Freelance Project, LifeBerry Shop E-commerce website

2017

• Developed an E-commerce website with admin panel using Ruby on Rails, integrated Pay2Go payment gateway.